Okay. Let's do it.
好，來吧
You're gonna regret this.
你會後悔的
All good? Here we go!
準備好了嗎？要開始囉！
Ready! Go!
預備！開始！
Whoa! That was fast.
哇！也太快了吧
-Every time! -Next!
-每一次耶！ -下一位！
That was faster than yesterday. Brutal.
比昨天還快，太猛了
I'm up.
換我
You got to win this time.
你這次一定會贏
-You got this, Takao. -Okay?
-說得沒錯，高尾 -好了嗎？
Ready! Go!
預備，開始！
-All right! -Wow!
-好耶！ -哇！
You can take Nakai.
你能挑戰中井了
-Yeah but Nakai is super strong. -Takao!
-對，但中井超壯的 -高尾！
Still too much for Nishikata. He's almost there.
這對西片來說太難了吧！ 他還差一點吧
You got this, Nakai.
你可以的，西片
Still too much for you.
這對你來說還是太難了吧
Okay?
準備好了？
Let's do it. Ready! Go!
開始囉，預備，開始！
Nakai.
西片
Oh? Could it be?
噢？有可能嗎？
All right!
好耶！
Wow.
哇
Seriously? That was incredible.
真的假的？太強了
You're arm wrestling was impressive. You've gotten stronger.
你今天比腕力好厲害喔 之前明明很弱的
I've been training everyday.
我每天都有健身
It must be from all those push-ups you do after being teased by me.
一定是你在被我捉弄後 做的那些伏地挺身的功勞
What? How do you know about that?
什麼？你怎麼知道？
I know everything about you, Nishikata.
你的事我全都知道哦
Are you okay? Did you catch a cold?
你還好嗎？你感冒了嗎？
I'm fine. Someone must be talking about me.
我沒事，一定是有人在背後談論我
The girls in our class have been gossiping about if you and I are dating.
班上的女生 都在討論你和我是不是在交往
Dating?
交往？
You and me?
你和我？
Yeah.
對
Is that bad?
這樣不好嗎？
No, it's just…
不，就只是…
So, you don't like people saying we're dating.
所以，你不喜歡別人說我們在交往
No, it's not that.
不，也不是
It's just that we aren't dating.
只是我們實際上並沒在交往
So, you wouldn't mind it if it were true.
所以，如果是真的，你也不介意
Then…
那麼…
Do you wanna date?
你想要交往嗎？
Wait a second.
等等
Why are you saying that? Cut it out.
你為什麼要這樣問？別這樣
Looks like more push-ups for you.
看來你要做更多伏地挺身了
Nishikata, you're burning up.
西片，你的額頭好燙啊
And you're a little red.
而且還有一點臉紅
Might be a cold.
也許是感冒了
Are you okay?
你還好嗎？
How about me?
那我呢？
You're a little hot too.
你也有一點燙
Maybe I got a cold too.
也許我也感冒了
Let's be careful.
我們都注意一點吧
Yeah. Both of us.
對，都要注意
GRADUATION CEREMONY
（畢業典禮）
I was shocked to hear about Takagi-san.
我聽到關於高木同學的消息 覺得好震驚啊
Takagi-san? Did something happen?
高木同學？她怎麼了嗎？
You didn't hear she's moving?
你沒聽說她要搬家了嗎？
What?
什麼？
She's moving at the end of March.
她三月底要搬家
I thought you would have heard considering how close you guys are.
我以為你一定已經知道了 你們這麼要好
Sorry to be the one to tell you.
抱歉啊，結果變成是我告訴你
Just forget it.
當我沒說好了
Forget it?
當你沒說？
Are you being serious?
真的嗎？
Yeah.
對
I heard from Mano. But a lot of our classmates already know.
我是從真野那裡聽到的 但班上很多同學都已經知道了
The guys too.
連男生也都知道
You are here
你在這裡
I am here
我在這裡
And when I turn around
而當我轉身
I see you smiling
我看見你微笑
The cherry blossoms bloom
櫻花盛開
The seasons changed
季節變換
But you remained
但你依然在那裡
Far, far in the distance
遙遠的地方
On the slope shimmering with heat
在冒著熱氣的坡道上
Even if the scenery were to change
就算風景改變
There are things that remain unchanged
也有不變的事物
Inside our hearts
長存在我們的心中
The happiness I receive
我因為遇見你
From meeting you
而得到的幸福
Let's walk together
讓我們並肩行走
And reflect upon it
然後回憶
In a year from now
在一年以後
In 10 years from now
在十年以後
From now until forever
從現在直到永遠
The happiness I receive
我因為遇見你
From meeting you
而得到的幸福
Let's walk together
讓我們並肩行走
And reflect upon it
然後回憶
In a year from now
在一年以後
In 10 years from now
在十年以後
Our memories remain the same
我們的回憶依舊
From now until forever
從現在直到永遠
I'm beat.
好累啊
What a moving performance.
真是感人的表演啊
But, man, the principal talked forever.
但是校長講個不停
-Tell me about it. -Right?
-就是說嘛 -對吧？
Was that necessary?
有那個必要嗎？
-No way. -My back hurts.
-完全沒有 -我的背好痛
Thanks.
謝謝
Hey.
各位
Someone carry these to the classroom.
需要有人幫忙把這些搬去教室
Nishikata, you got a spare hand?
西片，你有空嗎？
Carry these for me.
幫我搬這些
What?
什麼？
Don't "what" me.
還敢問“什麼？”
Yes!
是！
Sorry.
對不起
-I'll help too. -Off you go.
-我也來幫忙 -去吧
Let's go.
我們走吧
GRADUATION CEREMONY HALL
（畢業典禮會場）
What did you think of the ceremony?
你覺得畢業典禮怎麼樣？
I don't know.
我不知道
That will be us next year.
明年就換我們了
It will go by in a flash I'm sure.
時間肯定一轉眼就到了
Will you be sad to graduate?
我們畢業時，你會難過嗎？
I wonder.
不知道
How about you?
你呢？
What?
什麼？
Will you be sad?
你會難過嗎？
To graduate.
畢業的時候
Me?
我？
Yeah. I wonder.
嗯…我也不知道呢
What?
什麼？
Thank you.
謝謝
I'm so happy.
我好高興啊
She got his second button.
她得到他的第二顆鈕扣了
His second button?
他的第二顆鈕扣？
I'm beat.
好累啊
Overreacting as usual, Nishikata.
你還是和平常一樣誇張啊，西片
Nishikata, if someone asked for your second button…
西片，要是有人跟你要 你的第二顆鈕扣
Would you give it to them?
你會給她嗎？
Who knows? I don't think I'd be asked anyway.
誰知道？又沒有人跟我要
I see.
這樣啊
What?
怎麼了？
Can I have it?
那…可以給我嗎？
Fine.
好啊
You can have it.
我可以給你
I can?
可以給我啊？
Thanks. I'll take it.
那給我吧
Oh. The chair.
噢，你是說椅子
Of course. What did you think?
當然，不然你以為是什麼？
Nothing.
沒什麼
Did you think I meant your second button?
你該不會以為 我在說你的第二顆鈕扣？
Of course not.
當然不是
But I mean it.
但我說的其實是喔
I wanted to receive your second button.
我想要你的第二顆鈕扣
What?
什麼？
I wish I could graduate with you.
我希望可以和你一起畢業
What? Can't you?
為什麼？不能一起畢業嗎？
Yeah.
對
It's my father's job.
因為我爸爸的工作
After the closing ceremony, we're moving.
結業式後，我們就要搬家了
So, it was true.
所以，是真的
Did someone else already tell you?
有人已經告訴你了嗎？
Not everything.
大概提到而已
So that's why.
原來是這樣
I see.
好喔
TUESDAY MARCH 18TH
（3月18日星期二）
But the closing ceremony is really soon.
但結業式很快就要到了耶
It's all so sudden.
一切都好突然啊
Yeah.
嗯
Where are you moving?
你要搬去哪裡？
Hmm?
嗯？
Where will you go?
你要去哪裡？
Close by? Far away?
很近？還是很遠？
Paris.
巴黎
Paris? France?
巴黎？法國？
You're kidding right?
你在開玩笑吧？
You're just teasing me again.
你又在捉弄我了
I wish that were the case.
要是開玩笑就好了呢
As some of you may have heard, because of her father's job,
相信有些同學已經聽說了 由於高木同學爸爸工作的關係
Takagi-san will be moving at the end of the third semester.
她在第三學期結束後就要搬家了
It will be the closing ceremony soon, so let's send her off cheerfully.
結業式很快就要到了 讓我們歡送她吧
Okay!
好！
His middle years, changing from the destructive lifestyle of his past…
他在中年時期 一改他過去消極的生活方式…
So, Takagi-san really is leaving this island soon.
所以，高木同學 真的就要離開這座島了
Nishikata, where's your textbook?
西片，你的課本呢？
Oh, right.
噢，對
And in the final years of Dazai's life…
在太宰治人生的最後幾年…
Did you forget it?
你忘記帶了嗎？
Want to put our desks together?
要把我們的桌子併起來嗎？
…and unchanging even after the war…
…且在戰爭後仍然不變…
Yeah.
好啊
Thanks.
謝謝
Isn't this hard for her?
高木同學不會難過嗎？
She seems to be having more fun than ever.
她看起來比平常還要開心的樣子
THIS IS FUN
（好開心）
What?
什麼？
BECAUSE I'M CLOSER TO YOU THAN EVER
（因為這是我第一次靠你這麼近）
Wait, no way. This is Takagi-san after all.
等等，不可能，這可是高木同學啊！
She's trying to tease me again.
她又想捉弄我了
What?
什麼？
She isn't teasing me?
她不是在捉弄我？
It's for real?
她是認真的嗎？
AND I CAN TEASE YOU MORE THAN EVER
（這樣我要捉弄你就更方便了）
Damn it!
可惡！
She can "tease me."
她要“捉弄我”
-LET'S WALK HOME TOGETHER TODAY -OKAY
（今天像之前一樣一起走回家吧 好啊）
Where's your umbrella, Takagi-san?
高木同學，你的雨傘呢？
I forgot it.
我忘記帶了
You didn't know it was supposed to rain today?
你不知道今天會下雨嗎？
Yeah.
嗯
I didn't know.
我不知道
So, can I?
所以，可以嗎？
Can you what?
可以什麼？
That.
那個
Can I share yours?
我可以跟你一起撐嗎？
What?
什麼？
I don't mind.
我是不介意
Isn't your shoulder getting wet? Are you even under the umbrella?
你的肩膀是不是濕了啊？ 你真的有在幫自己撐傘嗎？
I'm fine.
我沒關係
You're all wet.
你都濕透了
You'll catch a cold.
不行，這樣你會感冒的
We don't have many more chances to go home together like this.
我們像這樣一起回家了 已經沒幾次了呢
I guess so.
好像是喔
The truth is…
其實
I knew it all along.
我一直都知道
Knew what?
知道什麼？
That it would rain today.
今天會下雨
You did?
真的啊？
Then why didn't you bring an umbrella?
那你為什麼不帶傘？
Because I knew yours was big enough for two.
因為我知道你的傘可以幫兩個人遮雨
What?
什麼？
Just like how you pretended to forget your textbook today.
就像你今天假裝忘記帶課本一樣
You knew that?
原來你都知道啊？
I was wondering why you didn't take it out.
我還在想，你為什麼不拿出來
By the way, Takagi-san…
對了，高木同學
Yeah? What is it?
嗯？什麼事？
That you're moving…
你要搬家的事
Why didn't you tell me first?
為什麼沒有先告訴我？
It's nothing.
沒事
I wanted to hear it from you.
我希望聽你親口告訴我
Such an important thing.
這麼重要的事
I love the rain.
我喜歡下雨天
The sound of rain on an umbrella.
喜歡雨落在傘上的聲音
All the different sounds mixing together.
所有不同的聲音混在一起
The smell of rain.
雨的氣味
It's so peaceful.
令人感到平靜
All right. I've decided.
好，我決定了
I promise not to look sad in front of her until she leaves.
在高木同學離開前，我絕對 不要在她面前表現出傷心的樣子
Just like always.
就像我一直以來那樣
I'll act the way I always do.
我要表現得和平常一樣
There are things that remain unchanged
也有不變的事物
Inside our hearts
長存在我們的心中
The happiness I receive
我因為遇見你
From meeting you
而得到的幸福
Let's walk together
讓我們並肩行走
And reflect upon it
然後回憶
In a year from now
在一年以後
In 10 years from now
在十年以後
Our memories remain the same
我們的回憶依舊
From now until forever
從現在直到永遠